Doug Campbell

🗣 Columbia, South Carolina, United States 🗷 dcampbellcreative@gmail.com 🛘 8436801296 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/douglass-campbell/

https://www.dougcampbell.io/

SUMMARY

Front End Developer with over a decade of graphic design experience and 6 plus years of business ownership experience. Bachelor's in Visual Communication. Certification in Full Stack Development. Passion for creating responsive sites and applications using React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Quick learner who thrives on finding creative ways to solve problems.

EXPERIENCE

UI Development Contributor

September 2022 - Present, Denver, CO - Remote

- · Implemented Mantine UI component library (100+ React components) to create complex UI elements, for React application, by reading the documentation, creating a development environment, and writing code.
- · Translated Figma designs into fully responsive pages and React components, using Matine UI's Styles API and CSS-in-JS.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Collaborated with team members to develop features from Jira tickets and user stories through frequent communication and weekly development meetings.}$

Frontend Software Engineering Intern Shopl

August 2022 - November 2022, Atlanta, GA - Remote

- Developed a UI from Figma files using NextJS, CSS modules, and Wix Editor X.
- · Collected data, created regular expressions, and wrote JavaScript web-scraping snippets to integrate 100 shopping sites into extension.
- \cdot Participated in team meetings 3 times weekly to discuss progress and plan future work.

Owner Operator

Hwy 55 Burgers, Shakes, and Fries

December 2015 - February 2022, Lugoff and Elgin, SC

- · Increased customer engagement and sales by developing marketing materials for various mediums including billboards, social media, and print.
- · Operated 2 Hwy 55 franchises, regularly in top 5 percent volume in South Carolina. Adapted business model to prosper during pandemic, grew sales by 10 percent operating without indoor dining.
- · Responsible for hiring, training, financial and quality management and a staff of over 40 employees.

Graphic Designer

Dew Learning, LLC.

October 2013 - June 2014, Charleston, SC - Remote

- Created 50 plus interactive lessons as part of an online home school curriculum using Adobe Creative Suite and a proprietary content management system.
- Ensured consistent design across multiple lessons and various subjects.
- · Collaborated with colleagues, project managers and 10 plus teachers daily to create an immersive learning experience for students.

PROJECTS

Website and Chrome Extension

Shopl · August 2022 - Present

- · Improved user conversion by creating a frontend website with a user-friendly interface.
- · Wrote 40+ JavaScript functions to scrape web data for extension.
- Built a website and chrome extension by learning new tools like Figma, NextJS, and Wix Editor X to increase productivity by 20% and allowing me build a website in less than 10 hours.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certification

CareerFoundry · Online · 2022

Bachelor of Arts, Visual Communications

Minor in Graphic Design · University of South Carolina · Columbia, SC · 2012

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, JavaScript, React, NextJS, HTML5, CSS3, TailwindCSS, WebFlow, Editor X, NodeJS, Git, Github, MongoDB, Postman, AGILE